Guide to the Erasmus Hall Records 1325–1989 (bulk circa 1775–1975) MS 201
New-York Historical Society
- "Archives of Erasmus Hall High School"
  - Chronicles of Erasmus Hall (1906)
    - Chronicles of Erasmus Hall, 1906 (Offsite-box RC-11, Volume Chronicles (1906))
      • one leatherbound copy
    - [Letters], 1906 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Correspondence Relating to the Chronicles of Erasmus Hall (1906))
      A folder of letters pertaining to the published volume entitled Chronicles of Erasmus Hall High School. The majority are letters of thanks to Dr. Gunnison for sending complimentary copies of the Chronicles to various officials and libraries. There are, however, some letters from old Flatbush residents interesting for the signatures and for the contents.
    - [Photograph], 1909 (Offsite-box RC-9a, Folder Original photographs used in the Chronicles)
      Original photograph of persons connected with the history of Erasmus Hall, used for publication in the Chronicles of Erasmus Hall, published 1906.
  - Chronicles of Erasmus Hall (1937)
    - The Chronicles: A History of Erasmus Hall High School from 1906 to 1937 (Offsite-box RC-11, Volume Chronicles (1937))
      Published by the General Organization, Erasmus Hall High School, Brooklyn, 1937. 160 p.
      • two softbound copies
  - Chronicles of Erasmus Hall (1987)
    - The Chronicles of Erasmus Hall High School, 1937–1987 (Offsite-box RC-11, Volume Chronicles (1987))
      Published by the New York City Board of Education, 1987.
  - Coins
    - An English coin picked up on the Vanderveer farm in Flatbush..., 1742 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Three pieces of Currency...)
      ... which was undoubtedly dropped by the Hessian and British soldiers who were quartered in the Vanderveer homestead after the Battle of Long Island, 1776. The coin is inscribed on the obverse: "Georgius II Rex" and on the reverse: "Hibernia 1742." (Note: the Vanderveer homestead stood at 1159 Flatbush Avenue until 1911.)
  - Columbia Scholastic Press Association
    - Medalist Certificates awarded to The Erasmian, 1952–1963 (Offsite-box RC-3a, Folder Awards)
  - Commentator
    - "The Commentator," published by the Effodians History Club of Erasmus Hall, 1937–1946 (Offsite-box RC-4a, Folder Cavalcade, Commentator (history publications))
      • Vol. 2, no. 2 (Spring 1937) [3 copies]
      • Vol. 3, no. 1 (January 1938) [2 copies]
      • Vol. 4, no. 1 (January 1939)
      • Vol. 4, no. 2 (June 1939)
      • June 1945 [2 copies]
      • June 1946
  - Committee to Preserve Flatbush Town Hall
    - Miscellaneous literature, [1970s?] (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Committee to Preserve Flatbush Town Hall)
      Miscellaneous literature issued by the Committee to Preserve Flatbush Town Hall and its successor, the Town of Flatbush Civic and Cultural Assoc., Inc. (TOFCCA). Complete run of the Committee's publication, The Spirit of Flatbush, is included.
  - Compton-Mackenzie, Nell (English actress)
    - Letter to Marjorie Weirich, 1917 January 26 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Autographs)
      Holograph, 3 pg. letter to Miss Marjorie Weirich, dated "Maxine Elliotts Theatre, Jan. 26th, '17," in which she thanks Miss Weirich for complimenting her performance in "Great Catherine." She also speaks of her eldest brother, Compton Mackenzie, the famous English author, and recommends some of his books.
  - Confederate States of America—Currency
    - Three envelopes containing original pieces of Confederate currency, [1862–1865] (Offsite-box RC-10a, Folder Currency of the Confederate States of America)
      • Six pieces presented to the library of EHHS in 1913 by the U.S. Treasury
      • Seven pieces in envelope marked "Samples of Confederate Money Captured during the War of the Rebellion, 1862–1865, in the field."
      • Fourteen pieces in another envelope.
  - Cooperation in Government Medals
    - [Programs], 1929, 1933 (Offsite-box RC-3a, Folder Awards)
      • Cooperation in Government Presentation: The Annual Gold Medallion for 1928 to Louis Heaton Pink, Erasmus Hall High School, October 23, 1929. (12 copies of program)
      • Cooperation in Government, Inc. Presentation of a Gold Medallion to Genevieve Beavers Earle, Erasmus Hall High School, May 26, 1933 (3 copies of program)
  - Corey, Grace L. (EHHS administrative assistant)
    - [Miscellaneous material], 1964, undated (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder Grace Corey, administrative assistant)
      • List of references for material on Grace Corey in various EHHS publications.
      • Also, photograph, black and white, 5 x 7".
      • Program for Testimonial Luncheon, May 9, 1964
  - Cowenhoven, John R.
    - Inventory of the estate of John R. Cowenhoven of the township of "Broucklin"..., 1778 June 1 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Cowenhoven Family #1)
      Inventory of the estate of John R. Cowenhoven of the township of "Broucklin," as appraised by Engelbert Lott, Sr. and Jr., June 1, 1778. This 11 page inventory adds up to the fantastic sum of £15699, and includes an array of household goods befitting such a wealthy man.
      8 x 13" notebook without covers, completely split horizontally: needs repair. Signed by "Engelbart Lott" and "Engt Lott Junr."
    - Receipt book of John R. Cowenhoven, 1783–1786 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Cowenhoven Family #2)
      Receipt book of John R. Cowenhoven, 4 ¼ x 6 ½", leatherbound, 1783–1786.
      The receipts for money paid by Cowenhoven are signed by residents of early Flatbush and Brooklyn, including: Cornelius Van Duyn, Peter Kouwenhoven, John Voorhees, Peter Stuyvesant, Simon Duryee, Hendrick Suydam, Peter Lefferts, Cornelius Vanderveer, Nicholas Schenck, Matthew Clarkson, Wilhelmis [sic] Stoothoff.
    - Two receipts for medical care, 1791–1793 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Cowenhoven Family #1)
      • From Dr. N. J. Barbarin, 1791–92.
      • From Dr. Saml. Bard, 1792–93.
      Note: this John R. Cowenhoven is obviously not the same man as the John R. Cowenhoven whose estate inventory (see Cowenhoven, John R.) is dated 1778.
  - Cowenhoven, Capt. Rem
    - Miscellaneous receipts, 1771–1779, 1782 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Cowenhoven Family #1)
      Including:
      • Receipt from James Hay, Jr., Barrack Office, New York, 20 June 1782, for 9 cords 7 feet wood cut by Rem Cowenhoven, "being his full Quota for March Quarter."
      • Four paid doctor bills of Rem Cowenhoven, 1771–1779, two from Dr. Van Zynderen.
    - Receipt book of Rem Cowenhoven, 1775–1783 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Cowenhoven Family #2)
      Receipt book of Rem Cowenhoven, 4 ¼ x 6 ½", leatherbound, 1775–1783.
      The receipts for money paid by Cowenhoven are signed by residents of early Flatbush and Brooklyn. Among the signatures are: Francis Bogardus, Daniel Onderdonck, Abraham and Engelbert Lott, Peter Goelet (of N.Y.), George and Jeronemus A. Remsen, John Polhemus, Gerrit Zabriskie, Jacobus Hegeman, Peter Lefferts, etc.
    - Letter from William Axtell to Rem Cowenhoven, 1780 April 10 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Cowenhoven Family #1)
      Col. William Axtell, signed, holograph letter dated "Flat Bush 10th April 1780," instructing Capt. Rem Cowenhoven to arrest "Any Person presuming to cut wood from off the Land of any Inhabitant in your District.. ."
    - Two Revolutionary War documents, 1782 April 1, undated (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Cowenhoven Family #1)
      • Holograph, signed instructions, dated 1 April 1782, ordering that "Every Inhabitant of the town of Bushwicke, Capt. Lott's District that have waggons and horses that they Immediately Cart into the Magazine at Brooklyn ferry all the Remainder of the Quota of fuel and Continue until the Whole is finished—hereof fail not as you will answer if Contrary... ."
      • Statement signed "Rem Couwenhoven Capt." to certify that "Tunis Bergen on Duty at Brooklyn Ferry as before May 1st & 15th at four in Afternoon."
  - Cowenhoven family
    - Notebook, 1782–1824 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Cowenhoven Family #1)
      18th century notebook, 8 x 13", containing the following:
      • Estate papers of Rem Cowenhoven (q.v.) of Brooklyn, including a copy of his will, dated Jan. 14, 1782, and a full inventory of his estate. (14 pages)
      • "Expenditures of the Wind-mill," 1803–4. (3 + 1 pages.) See Vanderveer Family—Wind Mill for full description.
      • Expenses paid out of Rem Cowenhoven's estate, 1783–85, as administered by John R. Cowenhoven (8 pages).
      • Expenditures and receipts in the estate of Rutgert A. Van Brunt, as administered by John C. Vanderveer, 1818–1824. One item in the estate which sold for $200 to John E. Lott: "a Negro man named Jack & negro woman named Beth with three small children." (2 pages).
  - Cowl, Jane (1883–1950) (Shakespearean actress)
    - Inscribed photograph, 1926 (Offsite-box RC-14b, Folder Cowl, Jane (Shakespearean actress))
      Framed, autographed photograph inscribed to Erasmus Hall High School, 1926. She was a student at Erasmus Hall. (Frame discarded November 2021.)
  - Currency
    - [Colonial currency], 1775, 1776 (Offsite-box RC-6a, Folder Three pieces of Currency...)
      • Fifteen shilling note issued by the Colony of New Jersey, 20 Feb. 1776. Signed by John Hart of Hopewell, N.J., a signer of the Declaration of Independence.
      • "Continental Currency" of "The United Colonies," entitling the bearer to "eight Spanish milled dollars," and dated Nov. 29, 1775, at Philadelphia.
      • "State of New York, New York Currency," good for three Spanish milled dollars. Aug. 13, 1776.
  - Currier and Ives lithograph
    - "The Old Stone House, L.I., 1699", [1848–1856] (Offsite-box RC-13)
      Original lithograph issued by Nathaniel G. Currier, depicting the Old Stone House at Gowanus, L. I. (now part of Brooklyn, N.Y.), built in 1699, which was the site of fighting during the Battle of Long Island.
      This framed lithograph had a label on the back of the frame reading "For John Lefferts." It may have been a gift of either the Lefferts or Zabriskie families.
  - Dish [NOT PRESENT]
    - Small dish made of Austrian china with full color view of Erasmus Hall, Flatbush, N.Y., circa 1900 (Box [unknown])
      Manufactured for F. A. Lippold, Flatbush, N.Y.
      n.d., but c. 1900. Lippold produced and sold a variety of Flatbush souvenirs in this period, including post cards of old Flatbush scenes (see Flatbush—Views. Postcard album.. .)
      Recorded as being in Drawer 15.
  - Ditmas or Van Nuys Homestead, Brooklyn, N.Y.
    - Ditmas or Van Nuys Homestead, Brooklyn, N.Y., [1935–1943] (Offsite-box RC-7, Frame Ditmas or Van Nuys Homestead)
      The Ditmas or Van Nuys Homestead, Brooklyn, N.Y. Etching made by William Hicks. W.P.A. Federal Art Project, N.Y.C. 6 x 8", framed to 12 x 13 ½".
  - Doggett, Allen B. (EHHS art instructor, 1896–1926)
    - Illustrations for Hans Brinker or The Silver Skates: A Story of Life in Holland, circa 1895 (Offsite-box RC-24)
      Forty-one pen-and-ink and charcoal illustrations by Doggett for Mary Mapes Dodge's novel Hans Brinker or The Silver Skates: A Story of Life in Holland. Parenthetical numbers following each illustration in the list below correspond to page numbers in the New Amsterdam Edition of Hans Brinker, published by Charles Scribner's Sons in 1904. A copy of the book, with an Erasmus Hall Library bookplate, is included in the box with Doggett's illustrations.
      • The Race (frontispiece)
      • Fishing Through the Ice (1)
      • Even the Horses wear a Wide Stool on Each Hoof (12)
      • Children at Play in Holland (13)
      • The Pole of a Dutch Wagon (14)
      • On the Dunes (17)
      • "We cannot take this Money," panted Hans (39)
      • Peter calling the Roll (85)
      • Greasing Sled-Runners with an Oiled Rag (90)
      • On the Frozen Zuyder Zee (97)
      • A Guard (98)
      • The Tulips in Bloom (99)
      • A Summer-House in Holland (103)
      • "It's Gone!" (114)
      • "I thank you, Hans Brinker!" (120)
      • The Aanspreeker (133)
      • "There is a White Cushion" (134)
      • In the Cathedral (137)
      • An Ice-Boat (163)
      • A Warming-Pan (183)
      • Still the Thing Moves, Slowly, Slowly (186)
      • "There's your Man, mine Host" (191)
      • The Stadhuis at Leyden (208)
      • A Triptych (209)
      • Quentin Matsy's Well at Antwerp (223)
      • The Black Cavalry (229)
      • Peter bidding his Sister Good-by (247)
      • A Gust of Wind (252)
      • Playing Skittles (253)
      • The Meester Confers with his Assistant (263)
      • "It is right, Mynheer. I consent." (269)
      • Hilda and Gretel at the Cottage (276)
      • The Hidden Money was not there! (307)
      • "Huzza, Girls, I've found Work!" (321)
      • "Bury this" (325)
      • "I'm flying from my Country" (334)
      • Raff Brinker pays his Vrouw a Compliment (339)
      • Hans and the Meester (344)
      • "When I can serve you, Mynheer, I am ready" (347)
      • Every Man had his Pipe (353)
      • The Investigating Committee (381)
    - Artwork produced by some of Mr. Doggett's students, 1896–1898 (Offsite-box RC-7, Folder Art work made by EHHS students)
      Mostly watercolors of figures in different positions. Discovered in the EHHS tank room, 1956.
    - Plaster plaque with profile of Erasmus in bas-relief, sculpted by Allen B. Doggett [NOT PRESENT], 1896–1916 (Box [unknown])
      Plaster plaque, 7 ½ x 11", with profile of Erasmus in bas-relief; Allen B. Doggett, sculptor.
      Executed during the administration of Walter B. Gunnison, principal, 1896–1916, whose initials are worked into the design of the plaque.
    - [Obituaries and photograph], 1926, undated (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder Allen B. Doggett)
      • Brooklyn Daily Eagle, Oct. 4, 1926. Obituary of Allen B. Doggett [2 copies]
      • New York Times, n.d. Obituary of Allen B. Doggett.
      • 8 x 10" photograph (black and white) of the Allen B. Doggett memorial stained glass windows in his old Studio D in the Flatbush Ave. tower (now known as room 403).
  - Doolittle, Clara A. Cummings
    - Letters and scrapbooks, regarding her years at Erasmus Hall, circa 1900–04 (Offsite-box RC-3a, Folder Letters & Scrapbooks of Clara A. Cummings Doolittle)
  - Dutchman
    "The Dutchman," newspaper of Erasmus Hall High School. v. 1, no. 1 (1925) through v. 67 (sic), no. 3 (June 1974). Ceased publication with June 1974 issue. Issued irregularly, but approximately once a month; numbering is very irregular. Vols. 1–23 (1925–1941) are bound in four folio volumes. Issues from vol. 24 through the final issue of June 1974 are filed loose in a Hollinger file box, in chronological order. The Dutchman is the primary source for the history of the school for a fifty-year period.
    - Dutchman [bound volume], 1925–1931 (Offsite-box RC-19b)
      Vol. 1, no. 1 (May 1, 1925)–vol. 7, no. 27 (June 12, 1931)
    - Dutchman [bound volume], 1931–1935 (Offsite-box RC-19b)
      Vol. 8, no. 1 (October 16, 1931)–vol. 11, no. 26 (June 14, 1935)
    - Dutchman [bound volume], 1935–1939 (Offsite-box RC-19b)
      Vol. 12, no. 1 (October 4, 1935)–vol. 18, no. 10 (January 13, 1939)
    - Dutchman [bound volume], 1939–1941 (Offsite-box RC-19b)
      Vol. 19, no. 1 (February 24, 1939)–vol. 23, no. 8 (June 6, 1941)
    - Dutchman [loose issues], 1941–1974 (Offsite-box RC-20)
      Vol. 24, no. 1 (September 26, 1941) – vol. 47, no. 3 (June 1974).
      Complete except for the following issues:
      • v. 28, no. 3 (Oct.? 1943)
      • v. 31, no. 3 (Mar. 1945)
      • v. 32, no. 1 (Sept.? 1945)
      • v. 32, nos. 7–8 (Dec. 1945–Jan. 1946?) (published? )
      • v. 34, no. 5 (Dec.? 1946)
      • v. 36, nos. 5–6 (Dec. 1947–Jan. 1948?) (published? )
      • v. 46, no. 1 (Oct. 1, 1952) (mutilated copy on file)
      • v. 53, no. 3 (Nov. 30, 1956) (mutilated copy on file)
      • v. 57, nos. 4–5 (Dec. 1958–Jan. 1959?) (published? )
      • v. 64, no. 3 (Nov.? 1963)
      • v. 68, no. 3 (Nov.? 1966)
      • v. 70, no. 6 (June 1969) (defective copy on file)
    - Dutchman [microfilm], 1925–1941 (Offsite-box RC-19b)
      • reel 1: vol. 1, no. 1–vol. 11, no. 26 (May 1925–June 1935)
      • reel 2: vol. 12, no. 1–vol. 23, no. 8 (October 1935–June 1941)
    - "Novelist's Grant to Aid 2 Schools. [Sidney] Sheldon Provides $125,000 to Revive Student Papers in Brooklyn and Bronx," New York Times, 1988 November 20 (Offsite-box RC-19b, Folder Re: Dutchman)
  - Earle, Willis (EHHS English teacher, 1898–1934)
    - Letter to Dr. John R. McNeill, 1940 October 14 (Offsite-box RC-2, Folder Erasmus Hall High School—Faculty (Misc.))
      Two-page, holograph letter to Dr. John R. McNeill, postmarked North Thetford, Vt., Oct. 14, 1940.
      For obituary, see: Dutchman, v. 29, no. 4 (April 28, 1944), p. 1.
  - Erasmian, 1898–[1965?]
    The Erasmian, v. 1 (1898) to date. The literary magazine of Erasmus Hall High School.
    - Erasmian, v. 1–12, 1898–1910 (Offsite-box MS-10)
    - Erasmian, v. 13–21, 1910–1919 (Offsite-box MS-11)
    - Erasmian, v. 22–28, 1919–1926 (Offsite-box MS-12)
    - Erasmian, v. 29–35, 1926–1933 (Offsite-box MS-13)
    - Erasmian, v. 36–40, 1933–1938 (Offsite-box MS-14)
    - Erasmian, v. 41–47, 1938–1945 (Offsite-box MS-15)
    - Erasmian, v. 48–54, 1946–1952 (Offsite-box MS-16)
    - Erasmian, v. 55–67, 1952–1965 (Offsite-box MS-17)
    - Erasmian, v. 68, 1965– (Offsite-box MS-18)
    - Erasmian, 1899, 1973 (Offsite-box RC-3a, Folder Erasmian)
      • Subscription blank for the Erasmian, dated Oct. 20, 1899.
      • Invitation to Diamond Anniversary, 1973.
      • Folder of pictures and letters of faculty advisors.
  - Erasmus, Desiderius
    - "Adages," a collection of Latin phrases..., 1528, undated (Offsite-box RC-7)
      An original leaf from the edition printed in 1528 by Jerome Froben, Basle.
  - Erasmus, Desiderius—Portrait
    - Albrecht Dürer's famous engraved portrait of Desiderius Erasmus, executed 1526, circa 1600 (Offsite-box RC-7, Frame [Durer])
      This engraving was "pulled" about 1600, according to notation on the matte.
      Engraving about 8 x 10", framed to 18 x 23". Gift of Joseph Burger, 1960.
    - ["Erasmus von Rotterdam"], late 1800s (Offsite-box RC-3a, Folder Erasmus, Desiderius. Clippings, dedication of statue)
      Reproduction in color of a round portrait of "Erasmus von Rotterdam." Printed in Basel; n.d., but appears to be late 19th c.
    - [Holbein portrait of Erasmus], undated (Offsite-box RC-3b, Folder Erasmus by Holbein)
      Two full color, 8 x 10 (11 x 13 with mat) copies of the famous Holbein portrait of Erasmus which hangs in the Louvre.
  - Erasmus, Desiderius—Statue
    - "Erasmus Hall Unveils Statue of Its Patron," Brooklyn Daily Eagle, 1931 April 26 (Offsite-box RC-3a, Folder Erasmus, Desiderius. Clippings, dedication of statue)
    - Photograph of the original statue, 1955 January (Offsite-box RC-3a, Folder Erasmus, Desiderius. Clippings, dedication of statue)
      Photograph of the original statue of Erasmus in Rotterdam, Netherlands, from which the casting for the EHHS replica was made. Supplied by the Rotterdamsch Nieuwsblad, Jan. 1955.
  - Erasmus Hall Academy—100th anniversary of charter (1887)
    - Brooklyn Daily Eagle newspaper clippings, 1887 June (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Erasmus Hall—100th Anniversary)
      • "Erasmus Hall: The Coming Celebration of the Granting of its Charter." (Mon. Jun 13, 1887)
      • "Erasmus Hall Academy. Reception by the Pupils in the Flatbush Town Hall." (n.d., but must be June 16, 1887)
    - [Programs and invitation], 1887 June (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Erasmus Hall—100th Anniversary)
      • Program for Centennial Reception held at Flatbush Town Hall, Wed., June 15, 1887. (two copies)
      • Engraved invitation to Centennial celebration in Chapel of Reformed Dutch Church of Flatbush, June 16.
      • Program for Centennial Celebration held in Chapel of Reformed Protestant Dutch Church of Flatbush, June 16. (approx. 16 copies)
  - Erasmus Hall Academy—Advertisements
    - Erasmus Hall Academy—Advertisements, 1823?–1843 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Erasmus Hall Academy—Advertisements)
      • 1823? 8 x 9 ½" one pg. circular with engraving of Academy, describing the high standards of the Academy.
      • Brooklyn Daily Eagle, Oct. 26, 1841 (actually a facs. issued 1941) with adv't. of Erasmus Hall Academy on p. 1, col. 3.
      • New York American, Nov. 4, 1841 (original), with adv't of Academy on p. 1, col. 3.
      • _____, clipped adv't. of Academy, dated Aug. 19, 1843.
  - Erasmus Hall Academy—Architect
    - [Letter from William Hindley to John F. McNeill regarding supposed architect of Erasmus Hall Academy building], 1938 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Erasmus Hall Academy—History)
      When the Historic American Buildings Survey (HABS) prepared its report on Erasmus Hall Academy, c. 1940, it attributed the structure to Major Pierre C. L'Enfant, remembered as the designer of Washington, D.C. This attribution is followed by Alan Burnham in New York Landmarks (Middletown, Conn.: Wesleyan U. Press, 1963), p. 377.
      The compiler of this catalogue has found no contemporary record of Major L'Enfant's role in the design of Erasmus Hall Academy. The source of this attribution may have been one William Hindley, who wrote to Dr. John F. McNeill, the school's principal, in 1938, in an effort to convince McNeill that L'Enfant was indeed the school's architect, despite the admitted absence of "a written proof from that period; or a tradition—a manuscript—document—letter.. ." The tone of Hindley's letter suggests an obsession and eccentricity that would undermine one's belief in Hindley's credibility. Yet, the closeness in time of Hindley's letter to the preparation of the HABS report indicates that this letter may have influenced the attribution. Hindley's letter can be found in: Box: RC-1, folder: Erasmus Hall Academy—History.
  - Erasmus Hall Academy—Athletic Department
    - "Gentlemen's Physical Culture—Apparatus Needed", circa 1870s (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Academy Trustees' Correspondence)
      Estimate by Archibald Curlbertson, Instructor, of $50.00.
  - Erasmus Hall Academy—Boarding
    - [Letter and report], 1874 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Academy Trustees' Correspondence)
      • Holograph, signed letter from Mrs. E. T. Mack, Mar. 30, 1874, regarding the financial problems of the "boarding department," and asking the Trustees to relieve Mr. and Mrs. Mack of paying additional rent.
      • Also, report to Trustees by Committee appointed to examine the situation, dated Apr. 20, 1874. Signed Jno. D. Prince, C. L. Wells, H. L. Bartlett.
    - [Photographs of boarders], 1880s–1890s (Offsite-box RC-9a, Folder Erasmus Hall Academy—19th century group photos)
      Because of its financial difficulties, Erasmus Hall Academy took in adult boarders in the 1880s and 1890s, who had apartments in the old Academy building. Photographs of some of these boarders.
  - Erasmus Hall Academy—Catalogue
    - [Prospectus and catalogues], 1860–1891 (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Academy Trustees' Correspondence)
      • Howard, Rev. W. W. Prospectus of Erasmus Hall Academy. N.Y.: Smith, Woodman & Co., 1860. 12 p.
      • Circular and Catalogue of Erasmus Hall Academy. Brooklyn: Union-Argus Printing, 1881. 24 p.
      • Circular and Catalogue of Erasmus Hall Academy. Brooklyn: Martin & Niper, 1885. 24 p. [3 copies]
      • Circular and Catalogue of Erasmus Hall Academy. Brooklyn: Martin & Niper, 1886. 24 p. (& insert)
      • Erasmus Hall Academy. Circular for 1891. n.p., 1891. 4 l.
    - Prospectus for school year beginning 1874 [3 copies] (Offsite-box RC-1, Folder Academy Trustees' Correspondence)
  - Erasmus Hall Academy—Charter
    - Original charter of Erasmus Hall Academy, granted by the Regents of New York State and signed by Governor George Clinton, 1787 November 20 (Offsite-box RC-13)
      Illustrated on page 35 of the "Chronicles of Erasmus Hall" (1906).